Finding Aid for the Ralph Edwards Productions Production Records PASC.0336
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ralph Edwards Productions production records
1940-circa 2001
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ralph Edwards Productions
PASC.0336
156.5 Linear Feet (313 boxes)
The collection consists of materials pertaining to the various Ralph Edwards Productions projects such as Truth or Consequences, This is Your Life, and Name That Tune.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9963323113606533
Biographical Note
Ralph Edwards was born near Merino, Colorado, in 1913, moving with his family to Oakland, California, when he was 12. He worked his way through college at radio stations in Oakland and San Francisco, graduating from the University of California at Berkeley in 1935 with a Bachelor of Arts degree in drama. Edwards moved to New York in 1936 and became one of radio's busiest announcers, doing as many as 45 network shows a week. In 1940, in response to this hectic pace, Edwards created, produced and hosted the landmark audience participation show "Truth or Consequences".
The show's great popularity led to his appearance in the Lucille Ball-Victor Mature film Seven Days' Leave (1942). He moved the show and his production company to Hollywood in 1945, where he made three more films for RKO: Radio Stars on Parade (1945), The Bamboo Blonde (1946) and Beat the Band (1947), all with Frances Langford. His big-screen career took a decided back seat in 1948, when Edwards first brought to the air his other long-running show, "This Is Your Life" (1952). On radio for its first two years, Edwards took the program to NBC-TV in 1952, where it remained until 1961, winning two Emmys (he also hosted a syndicated version from 1971-1973). His last feature film appearance came in the Susan Hayward MGM bio-pic of Lillian Roth, I'll Cry Tomorrow (1955), which ends with a recreation of Roth's appearance on "This Is Your Life" (1952).
Edwards' television career began in earnest in 1950, when "Truth or Consequences" (1950) aired one season on CBS-TV and earned the first Emmy awarded for an audience participation show. He turned over host duties to Jack Bailey in 1954 and, in 1956, launched the career of Bob Barker as host of the daytime version. Edwards, also well-known for his extensive charitable and philanthropic activities, became one of TV's most prolific producers. Biographical note courtesy of IMDB.com.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of materials pertaining to the various Ralph Edwards Productions projects such as Truth or consequences, This is your life, and Name that tune.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Series 1. This is Your Life, 1952-1987
Series 2. Truth or Consequences, 1940-1988
Series 3. The Cross-Wits, 1975-1980
Series 4. End of the Rainbow, 1957-1958
Series 5. Funny Boners, 1954-1955
Series 6. Face to Face
Series 7. Knockout, 1977-1978
Series 8. Name That Tune
Series 9. Press Your Luck
Series 10. Punchliners
Series 11. Mouthtrap
Series 12. The People's Court
Series 13. The Ralph Edwards Show, 1952
Series 14. That's Show Biz, 1985 October 23
Series 15. About Faces, 1960-1961
Series 16. So You Think You've Got Troubles
Series 17. Superior Court, 1986-1989
Series 18. Who in the World, 1962
Series 19. Walk Across the Land, 1961 December
Series 20. Portrait of an American, 1963
Series 21. Human Thing to Do, 1961
Series 22. Fatasies Fulfilled
Series 23. Going, Going, Gone
Series 24. Sing Out, 1960 October 13
Series 25. Woody Woodbury Show, 1967
Series 26. Ungame Show, 1977 March 10
Series 27. That Crazy Show, 1977 April 14
Series 28. It Could Be You, 1956-1961
Series 29. Place the Face
Series 30. Wide Country, 1962-1963
Series 31. Beadle's About, 1986. 1 folder
Series 32. Television's Good Housekeeping, 1972-1973
Series 33. In Session
Series 40. Ralph Edwards
Series 41. Bob Barker
Series 50. Business Papers
Television producers and directors -- United States -- Archives.; Ralph Edwards Productions -- Archives
- This is Your Life, 1952-1987; Series 1.
  Scope and Contents note
  This Is Your Life is a television documentary series hosted by its producer, Ralph Edwards. It originally aired in the United States from 1952 to 1961, and again in 1972 on NBC. It originated as a radio show airing from 1948 to 1952 on NBC Radio. A version of it continues a very long run in the United Kingdom starting in 1955, and another version is still running in Australia. It has also been broadcast from time to time in New Zealand and Scandinavia. Concept: The format of the show consisted of the host, who would surprise someone (usually a celebrity or public figure, occasionally an ordinary citizen) and, consulting his "red book", conduct a biography of the subject in a television studio. The subject would be presented with family members and old friends, reunited with old acquaintances, and often shed a tear when a personal tragedy was recounted.
  - Research Material, Scripts and Sound Recordings, Subseries 1.
    This sub-series consists of research materials, scripts and sound recordings of specific episodes. General sound recordings are found in the Sound Recordings sub-series.
    - Gordon MacRae and Paul Anka Research Publications (Box 307, Folder 5)
    - Guest Subject Suggestion Letters, 1956-1961 (Box 307, Folder 4)
    - Lionel Hampton Research Material, 1955 (Box 307, Folder 5)
      American Red Mogen David For Israel fundraising campaign.
    - Lowell Thomas Magazine Article, 1979 January (Box 306, Folder 5)
    - Notes on Possible Show Subjects (Box 296, Folder 1)
      Includes notes on the following: Martha Logan; Reverend J. J. Cacopardo;Joel McCrea;Dr. R.H. Bruni; Dick Richard, and Casey Shawhan.
    - Notes on Possible Show Subjects (Box 296, Folder 2)
      Includes notes on the following: Governor Frank Clement; Rose Buckner; Dr. James Whitcomb Brower, and Gene Austin.
    - Notes on Possible Show Subjects (Box 296, Folder 3)
      Includes notes on the following: Helen Sawyer Campbell; Amos Baker; Dr. Morton Robbins; Carl Loeb; Vaal Stark, and Dr. Richard Castell.
    - Panorama, 1949 June 14; streaming audio (Box 236)
      Annotated script. 2 copies. Audio
      General note
      Radio broadcast
    - Radio Program Pilot, script (Box 233)
    - Research Files, 1963 May; 1 folder (Box 232)
    - Show Subject Research Notes (Box 295, Folder 2)
    - Show Subject Suggestions, 1955-1956 (Box 295, Folder 5)
    - Stan Surber Show Guest Suggestion Papers, 1959 (Box 307, Folder 4)
      Includes clippings, and letters of recommendation.
    - United Kingdom Episodes: R. Davies - P. Field (Box 282)
      Scripts
    - United Kingdom Episodes: P. Field-K. Horne (Box 283)
    - United Kingdom Episodes: D. Huskin-Lord (Box 284)
    - United Kingdom Episodes: J. Loss-A. Milbourne (Box 285)
    - United Kingdom Episodes: Freddie Mills - David Park (Box 293)
    - United Kingdom Episodes: A. Pearson - A. Rowe (Box 294)
    - Updates on Past Subjects (M-Z) (Box 301, Folder 5)
    - Updates on Past Subjects (A-L) (Box 303, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. Alfred Abeles, 1958 October 8 (Box 63)
      script; research notes
      Subject is a "mother" to displaced refugees. Program no. 307.
    - Nellie Logan Adkins, 1955 November 24 (Box 63)
      Subject is a schoolteacher.
    - Daniele Alberghetti, 1955 November 23 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Ettor Verna,friend, famous opera coach; Anna Maria Alberghetti, daughter, actress, concert singer; Carla Alberghetti, daughter, singer; Rabbi Dr. Marcus Breger, friend.
      Subject is the patriarch of a musical family.
    - Eddie Albert, 1958 October 15 (Box 63)
      Subject is a star of film, television and stage and is a singer. Guests include: Margo Albert, wife, Broadway and film actress; Mickey Finn, Actor, former L.A. policeman; ran youth clubs for underprivileged kids; Teddy Hart, Actor, comedian.
    - Ben Alexander, 1958 March 12 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Jack Bailey, host of Queen for a Day; Edwin Shallert, Friend, former movie critic with L.A. Times - now lecturer at UCLA; Jack Webb, Actor, co-star of TV's "Dragnet".
      Subject is a child film star.
    - Steve Allen, 1958 September 24 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Richard Kiley, TV and movie actor; Roxy La Rocca, Former vaudevillian ("Wizard of the Harp").
      Subject is a television personality.
    - Norman Alley, 1960 November 15 (Box 63)
      script; research notes.
      Subject is a photographer.
    - Norman Alley, 1961 January 1 (Box 236)
    - Fran Allison, 1953 May 20 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Sara Berner, Actress, comedienne; Frank Wisbar, Head of Fireside Theatre Productions.
      Subject is the television star of 'Kukla, Fran & Ollie.'
    - June Allyson, 1971 July 19 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Gloria De Haven, Actress, movie star; Bonnie Waters, Friend since MGM days, was actress and showgirl, wife of composer and conductor John Green; Toni Holt, columnist and TV personality; Van Johnson, actor; Margaret O'Brien, actress, movie star; Joe Pasternak, movie producer.
      Subject is a film star.
    - Alicia Alonso, 1954 May 26 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Alexandra Fedorova, Her ballet teacher; Chase Lucia, Director of the Ballet Theatre in NYC; Igor Youskevitch, dancer.
      Subject is a ballerina.
    - Liz Ambridge, 1961 January 30; script; research notes (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode.
    - Morey Amsterdam, 1973 March 26 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Jack Carter, comedian; Richard Deacon, actor; Rose Marie, comedienne; Larry Matthews, child actor.
      Subject is a television star and comedian.
    - Florence Anderson, 1959 November 13 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Jeanette Dix, member of the Rockettes; Russell Downing, President of the Radio City Music Hall; Cary Grant, actor; Robert Weede, Friend, opera and Broadway singer (started as first baritone at the Music Hall, star of "The Most Happy Fella").
      Subject is a wardrobe mistress.
    - Andrea, 1975 September 26 (Box 220)
      Australian episode
    - Eamon Andrews, 1955 July 29 (Box 302)
      Script for the first in the English program series.
    - Dana Andrews, 1972 October 30 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: John Gavin, actor; Harold Russell, actor.
    - Major Daniel Angel, 1958 February 10 (Box 224)
      script; research notes. Subject is a film producer who suffers from Polio.
    - Ann-Margret, 1971 May 13 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Allan Carr, producer; George Sidney, movie producer and director; Roger Smith, actor.
      Subject is a stage and film star.
    - Colonel Mike Ansell, 1960 March 28 (Box 224)
      script; research notes. Subject is a leader of equestrian sport in Britain.
    - Joseph Anthony, 1956 May 2; script; research notes (Box 63)
      Subject is a teenage Korean refugee.
    - Susan Anton, 1984 March 21 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Dudley Moore, actor and comedian; Fred Silverman, former programming chief at CBS, ABC and NBC.
      Subject is an entertainer.
    - Demetros Apostolon, 1953 April 15; script; research notes (Box 63)
      Subject is an airplane crash survivor.
    - Canon Edmund Stephen Arbuthnott, 1959 October 5; script; research notes (Box 224)
    - Richard Arlen, 1961 February 8 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Johnny Benson, Ralph Edwards Productions staff member; Nancy Carroll; actress, movie star; Andy Devine, character actor; Sally Eilers, actress, movie star; A.C. Lyles, movie producer; George O'Brien, actor, movie star; Jack Webb, actor, producer.
    - Cliff Arquette, 1960 October 20 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Mike Arquette, actor, later changed his name to Lewis Arquette and is the father of Rosanna Arquette); Hugh Downs, Announcer for Jack Paar's "The Tonight Show"; Florence Henderson, Actress, singer and TV personality; Alexander King, TV personality, a regular on Jack Paar's "The Tonight Show"; Monroe "Hap" Manning, TV writer ("Laugh-In"); Jack Paar, TV host; Myrtle Vail, Creator, writer and star of radio show "Myrt and Marge".
    - Cliff Arquette, 1960 October 30 (Box 236)
      Annotated script.
    - Nicki and Mervyn Ashton, 1975 November 21; script; research notes (Box 220)
    - Arthur Askey, 1959 September 7; script; research notes. Subject is a comedian. (Box 224)
    - Richard Attenborough, 1962 November 25; script; research notes. Subject is a film producer and director. (Box 224)
    - Gladys Aylward, 1963 April 1; script. (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode. Subject is a evangelical Christian missionary to China.
    - Lew Ayres, 1956 January 4 (Box 63)
      script. Guests include: Ben Alexander, actor; William "Billy" Bakewell; Don Malmberg, TIYL staff member.
      Subject is a film star and decorated World War II Conscientious Objector.
    - Lou Babcock, 1953 November 4 (Box 63)
      script. Guests include: Billy Pierce, star pitcher for the Chicago White Sox.
      Subject is a school teacher.
    - Jim Backus, 1958 November 26 (Box 63)
      script; research notes. Guests include: Henriette Kaye, Wife - actress, sculptor; John Harding, Friend, actor, screenwriter; Jerry Hausner, actor (radio, TV, movies), plays Magoo's nephew Waldo in the cartoons and got Backus the job with UPA - now associate producer of "The Milton Berle Show".
      Subject is a radio/film star (Voice of 'Mr. Magoo')
    - Pearl Bailey, 1971 January 12 (Box 63)
      script. Guests include: Bill Bailey, tap dancer; Cab Calloway; Bob Finkel, producer of her TV show; Edgar Hayes, bandleader; Herb Jeffries, Vocalist, owned Flamingo Club in L.A.; Joe Louis, Former heavyweight boxing champion; Lloyd Philips, pianist; Peetney Redman, widow of musical arranger Don Redman; Nobel Sissel, bandleader; Ethel Waters, actress and singer.
      Subject is a singer.
    - John Logie Baird, 1957 October 28; script (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode. Subject was a Scottish engineer and inventor of the world's first practical, publicly demonstrated television system, and also the world's first fully electronic colour television tube.
    - Belle Baker, 1955 June 1 (Box 63)
      script. Guests include: Herbert Baker, songwriter and screenwriter; Murray Baker, professional manager of the Robbins Music Publishing Company; Eddie Cantor, entertainer; Gerald Marks, songwriter; Tony Martin, singer, actress; Sophie Tucker, singer, vaudevillian; Dora Weissmanactress, former singing comedienne in vaudeville; now plays part of Mrs. Herman on "The Goldbergs."
    - Capt. Devere Frank Baker, 1959 December 10; script (Box 63)
      Subject is a Mormon adventurer who sailed a raft to Hawaii.
    - Capt. DeVere Frank Baker, 1959 December 10 (Box 236)
    - Arthur Baldwin, 1962 October 16; script (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode. Subject was a director of the Great Western Railway.
    - Dick Bancroft, 1960 November 28; script; research notes (Box 224)
    - Ron Barassi, 1977 April 18; script; research notes (Box 220)
    - Captain David Barclay, 1960 February 29; script; research notes (Box 224)
    - John Barclay, 1959 November 9; script; research notes (Box 224)
    - Father Maria Barelli, 1961 October 9; script; research notes (Box 224)
    - Evelyn Bark, O.B.E., 1966 December 9; script; research notes (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode. Subject worked for the British Red Cross during and after World War II running a service to reunite people with lost friends and relatives, including survivors of the Belsen concentration camp.
    - Billy Barty, 1960 March 30; script; research notes. Guests include: Billy Curtis, "little person" actor; Spike Jones, Friend, comedy bandleader, actor, TV host; Barty was part of his group; Jerry Maren, "Little person", actor; plays chef "Little Oscar" for the Oscar Mayer Company; Tenor (opera star, concert singer, TV star), close friend; hosted "Ford Festival" TV show 1951-52 on which Barty appeared; Mickey Rooney, Movie star, friend of almost 30 years (Barty joined the cast of the "Mickey McGuire" comedies starring Rooney in 1929); Brent Wilson, Friend, manager. (Box 81)
      Subject is a film/television star, and is a little person.
    - Anne Baxter, 1972 September 12; script; research notes Guests include: Bette Davis, movie star, friend; appeared together in "All About Eve"; Penny Fuller, Actress; Larry Kasha, Broadway producer; Mary Lawrence, Friend and actress; Max Showalter, Friend, actor, songwriter. (Box 81)
    - Tom Beaks, 1962 January 22; script; research notes (Box 224)
    - Andrew Begay, 1950 May 23; streaming audio
      Subject is a World War II Navajo code talker.
      Episode no. 68.
    - Andrew Begay, 1950 May 23; script; research notes (Box 217)
    - Stephen Behan, 1962 November 19; script; research notes (Box 224)
    - Rene Belbenoit, 1955 May 4; script; research notes Guests include: Carroll Young, screen writer. (Box 81)
      Subject escaped from Devil's Island.
    - David Bell, 1957 December 30; script; research notes (Box 224)
    - Richie Benaud, 1975 October 17 (Box 220)
    - Johnny Bench, 1972 September 16 (Box 81)
      Scope and Content
      Guests include: Baseball players Pat Corrales, Fred Kendall; Bobby Goldsboro, singer; Gloria Loring, singer, and Don Zimmer, San Diego Padres baseball manager.
      Subject is a baseball player.
    - William Bendix, 1955 November 9 (Box 221)
      Subject is a film/radio/television star.
    - Rolf Benirschke, 1983 January 18 (Box 221)
      Subject is a football player.
      Guests include: football players Charlie Joiner, Louie Kelcher, and Ed Luther.
    - Hugh Bentley, 1958 May 14 (Box 221)
      Citizen against vice-hometown clean up.
    - Milton Berle, 1956 June 6 (Box 221)
      Subject is a television comedian.
      Guests include: Ben Grauer, radio and TV announcer; Irving Gray, personal manager and executive producer; Jerry Lewis, Comedian, actor; Dean Martin, Comedian, singer; Jan Murray, Comedian, friend, star of TV's "Dollar A Second; Lillian Roth, singer; Elizabeth Kennedy, first professional partner; Phil Silvers, actor, comedian.
    - Herschel Bernardi, 1971 July 1 (Box 221)
      Subject is a film/stage star.
      Guests include: Lola Albright, actress; Fay Bernardi, sister, character actress; Jack Bernardi, brother, actor, author, songwriter; Helen Beverly, actress; Roger Bowen, actor; Mike Buchanan, CBS Publicity Director; Sue Ann Langdon, actress; Boris Sagal, TV director; Craig Stevens, actor.
    - Sara Berner, 1952 December 10 (Box 221)
      Subject is a radio, film and television star.
      Guests include: Jack Benny, comedian; Spike Jones, comedy bandleader, actor, TV host; June Robbins, singer.
    - Acker Bilk, 1962 April 16 (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode. Subject is a clarinetist and jazz musician, who had a huge hit with a recording of his own composition Stranger on the Shore.
    - Gene Biscailuz, 1953 February 18 (Box 221)
      Subject is a Los Angeles County sheriff.
    - Stanley Bishop, 1959 December 14 (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode. Subject is a Fleet Street crime reporter.
    - Bill Bixby, 1971 September 8 (Box 221)
      Subject is a television star.
      Guests include: Brenda Benet Bixby, wife, actress; Brandon Cruz, actor; Jim Henerson, TV and film writer; Charles Jones, Hollywood songwriter; James Komack, producer; Dinah Shore, singer; Miyoshi Umeki, actress; Dick Valentine, actor; Ray Walston, actor; William Windom, actor.
    - Harry Blackstone, 1960 March 9 (Box 221)
      Subject is a magician.
      Guests include: Aubrey, slight-of-hand artist; Edgar Bergen, Ventriloquist, actor; vaudeville, radio star, started as magician.
    - Harold Blair, 1976 April 29 (Box 220)
    - Janet Blair, 1959 May 20 (Box 221)
      Subject is a film and television star.
      Guests include: Raymond and Royce Blackburn (Blackburn Twins), dancers, comedians, night club entertainers; Richard Eastham, Actor, singer; co-star in "South Pacific"; Nick Mayo, husband, Broadway producer; John Raitt, Singer, Broadway star; Esther Williams, movie star, famous swimmer.
    - Janet Blair, 1959 May 20 (Box 236)
      Subject is a film and television star. Guests include: Raymond and Royce Blackburn (the Blackburn Twins), dancers, comedians, night club entertainesr; their act with subject was named Billboard's Best New Nightclub Act of 194; Richard Eastham, actor, singer; Nick Mayo, husband, Broadway producer; John Raitt, singer, Broadway star; Esther Williams, movie star, famous swimmer.
    - Reginald Blanchford, 1959 February 23 (Box 224)
    - Mel Blanc, 1984 February 1 (Box 221)
      Subject does cartoon voices.
      Guests include: Chuck Jones, friend, animator, director; Milt Josefsberg, TV writer, producer; was writer for "The Jack Benny Show"; Rich Little, Friend, comedian, voice actor.
    - Lt. Edward N. Bliss Jr., 1957 April 17 (Box 221)
      Subject is a public defender.
      Guests include: Henry Greenburg, TV producer; William Rousseau, Producer of TV's "The Jane Wyman Show"; Donald S. Sanford, TV writer.
    - Mrs. "Freddy" Bloom, 1958 December 1 (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode. Subject is a journalist and author. THIS IS YOUR LIFE - 'Freddy' Bloom, journalist and author, was surprised by Eamonn Andrews at London's Playhouse Theatre. Freddy was interned in Japanese prison camps for three and a half years during the second world war.
      Following the war, Freddy gave birth to a daughter born profoundly deaf possibly due to the malnutrition she had suffered in the Japanese camps. She subsequently devoted her life to the needs of deaf children, supporting a small society which later became the National Deaf Children's Society.
    - Ann Blyth, 1959 April 1 (Box 221)
      Guests include: Dennis Day, singer, actor, comedian; Jane (Mrs. Ken Errair) Withers, Actress (TV and movies), former child star.
    - Professor Tom Bodkin, 1960 March 14 (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode. Subject was an Irish lawyer, art historian, art collector and curator.
      Bodkin was Director of the National Gallery of Ireland in Dublin from 1927 to 1935 and founding Director of the Barber Institute of Fine Arts in Birmingham from 1935 until 1952, where he acquired the nucleus of the collection described by The Observer as "the last great art collection of the twentieth century".
    - Frank L. Bogart, 1960 November 30 (Box 221)
      Subject is a railroad conductor.
    - Dr. George Foote Bond, 1955 June 22 (Box 221)
      Subject is a country doctor in the U.S. Navy.
      Guests include: Bob Thomas, Hollywood columnist for Associated Press.
    - Elizabeth "Betty" Boon, 1949 April 19; streaming audio (Box 217)
      script and audio
      Subject is an aspiring TWA hostess. Radio program.
    - Pat Boone, 1971 July 30 (Box 221)
      Guests include: Perry Como, singer actor; Don Murray, Actor, director of "The Cross and the Switchblade"; Randy Wood, founder of Dot Records.
    - Baron Boothby, 1963 October 14 (Box 224)
      U.K. Episode. Subject was a controversial Conservative MP for East Aberdeenshire. His tribute includes a recorded message from Noel Coward.
    - Ernest Borgnine, 1956 October 24 (Box 221)
      Guests include: Jerry Lewis, actor, comedian, Robert Porterfield, director of the Barter Theatre in Abingdon, VA; Fred Zinneman, director.
    - Ernest Borgnine, 1956 October 24 (Box 236)
      Annotated script. Subject is a film and television star.
    - Charles Boswell, 1960 June 15 (Box 221)
      Subject is a blind golfer.
      Guests include: Bob Hope, entertainer.